Guide to Carleen Hutchins papers M1734
Stanford University. Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 2. General Files: Correspondence, Clippings, Photos, Papers, Notes
  - Scientific - Sears: Scientific Apparatus, 1961-1963; Scott Paper Co., 1989-1991; Scott, Alan N., 1980-1983; Scott, Thornton, 1953-1971; Scott, William R., 1967-1992; Sears-Robuck Foundation, 1970 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Seattle – Selmer: Seattle, 1969-1970; Security-Reid, Inc., 1986-1996; Selch, 1992; Seifert, Howard, 1967-1969; Seiler, Jean, 1984; Selmer, Inc., 1975 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Shaffer – Sharp: Shaffer, Warren, 1982; Shankland, Robert S., 1941; Shapiro, S. E., 1967, Sharp Products (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Sharp - Shigo: Sharp, Ronald, 1980-1981; Sharp, William M., 1974; Shavin, David M., 1987; Sheppard, Leslie, 1972-1981; Shigo, Alex L., 1969-1985 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Shipping - Simmons: Shipping Information, Shobert, Erle I., 1967; Shoulder Rests; Siau, John F., 1977-1978; Sigma Alpha Iota, 1979-1982; Sigma Xi, Cornell Chapter, 1965-1987; Silberger, Marc, 1977-1981; Simmons, William, 1970-1990 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Sims - Slaby: Sims, William, 1972; Singh, Punita, 1986; Sinoski, Ted P., 1977-1982; Sirin, Vladislan, 1995-2002; 1995-2002; Sirr, Steven, 1996-2005; Sitar, 1967; Skalmierski, Bogdan, 1980-1981; Slaby, William, 1965-2003 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Slapin - State: Slapin, Margi, (Ramsey), 1982-1993; Slatkin, Mischa, 1976-1981; Slifkin, Miriam, 1987-1994; Slingerland, Francis W., 1985-1986; Sloan, Peter, 1995-1996; Smith College, 1973; Smith, Donald O., 1965-1968; Smith, Helen, 1973; Smith, Jack H., State Univ. of N.Y. Albany, 1980-1996 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Smith – Sound: Smith, Kellum J., 1964-1997; Smith, Wilber J., 1976; Smith, Lawrence R., 1970-1998; Snowden, J.C., 1976; Society for Strings Inc., Katherine s. Brockway, 1953-1954; Sodolorsky, Sergei, 1964; Sokolow, Rachel; Solmssen, Harold and Doreen, 1968; Somogy, Ervin, 1979; Soroka, Walter W., 1967; Soulez, Lariviere, Jean, 1980-1990; Soundcoat Company, 1970; Soundlab Electronics, 1991; Sound of Science, 1985-1986 (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - South Carolina University, 1969-1975 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - South - Stanford: South California Violin Makers, 1980; Southern California Association of Violin Makers, 1983- 1998; Spectro-Chem Inc., 1971; Sperati, Carleton A., 1990; Springer Verlag, 1973; Squier, Schilling and Skiff, 1966; Stancel, Al, 1985-1997; Stanfield, Milly B., 1964-1969; Stanford University, 1970-2000 (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Stanley Museum, 1987-2000 (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Stanzial - Štefcové: Stanzial, Domenico, 1995-1999; Stapelfeldt, Karsten, 1977; Stapley, Craig, 1974; Star-Ledger Newspaper, 1973-1998; State College PA., Lecture, 1977; Stauffer, Donald W. U.S. Navy Band, 1965; Stearns, Isaac, 197; Štefcové, Petre, 1991 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Steffanoff - Soltenberg: Steffanoff, Dan N., 1957-1981; Steger, John F., 1972-1973; Stein, Joseph, 1967-1988; Steinway and Sons, 1991; Steinway, Theodore, 1964-1976; Soltenberg, Robert W., 1970-1973 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Stough – Stoutenburgh: Stough, Bruce, 1995-1999; Stout, John L.; Stoutenburgh, Harry L., 1959-1962 (Box 59, Folder 1)
  - The Strad, 1953-1999 (Box 59, Folder 2)
  - Strad – String: The Strad, Advertising and Directory, 1992-1996; Strange, Allen, 1999; Street, Tison, 1987; Strings Magazine, 2004; String Information, 1973-1994; String Materials Research (Box 59, Folder 3)
  - String Players; Strings, Article, 1973; Strings, 1990-2005 (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - Strings - Sullivan: Strings Resource Guide, 1997-1998; String Quartets; Stroboconn, 1955; Strong, William J., 1982-1999; Strong, William Y., Jr., 1982-1996; Styro Sales, 1967; Suits, Mark W., 1979-1990; Sullivan Clipping Bureau; Sullivan, Walter, 1967-1996 (Box 60, Folder 1)
  - Summer Workshops I (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Summer Workshops II (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Summer Workshops III (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - S.U.N.Y. - Supek: S.U.N.Y, 1981; Suny-Buffalo State University, 1970-1973; Suominen, L, Finland, 1958; Supek, Louis R., 1983-1997 (Box 61, Folder 1)
  - Super Sensitive Musical String Co., 1967-1999 (Box 61, Folder 2)
  - Sussex – Sweden: Sussex, University of, 1970; Sussman, Theodore, 1981-1982; Suter, Alice, 1994-1997; Suzuki Assoc. of the Americas, 2005; Suzuki Assoc. School of Strings, 1977-1985; Suzuki, Hideo, 1991-1992; Swann, Fracis, 1965; Swann, W. F. G., 1945; Swanson, Florence L., 1975-1981; Sweden Composer Contest, 1981-1983 (Box 61, Folder 3)
  - Sweden - Szalay: Sweden Royal Academy of Music, Sound Generation, 1980-2002; Sweetman, Ian C., 1980-1984; Swets & Zeitlinger BV, 1985-1997; Switzen, Barrie Louise, 1996-2003; Switzerland; Szalay, Ralph, 1976-1977 (Box 61, Folder 4)
  - Szecsody - Taylor: Szecsody, Alex J., 1965-1968; Tangeman, Mrs. Robert S., 1974-1993; Tanglewood, 1997; Tarnóczy, Tamás, 1973-1998; Tartaglia, John, 1972-1973; Tate, Lisa, 1977; Taylor Residential List, 2003; Taylor, Bradley J., 1966; Taylor, Joseph, 1964 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Taylor - Tubis: Taylor Lisa, 1990; Taylor, Martha, 1975-1992; Taylor, Pauline A, 1974; Tove, Per-Arne, 1964-1965; Trusdell, C. 1960; Tseng, David, 1981-1982; Tubis, Arnold, 1980-1998 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - Ueltz - Upsala: Ueltz, Herbert, 1979-1986; Uhler, Lynn, 1964; Ultrasonics, 1973; Union Carbide; United States Information Agency, 1964; United States Department of State, 1972; United States News and World Report, 1997; United States Support Of Documents, 1957; United Technology, 1988-1999; Unity Concerts, 1973-1987; Uppsala, University, Karol Pelc, 1965; Upsala College, East Orange N. J. (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Utah - Van Zoest: Utah, University of, Robert M. Lee, 1970-1971; Valspar Corp., 1962; Vande Kopple, Julius, 1995-1998; Van Tienhoven, A., 1968-1971; Van Zoest, W. H., 1971-1975 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Vander - Veneklasen: Vander Poorten, Jacques, 1981-2002; Vantage Press, Inc.; Varga, Laszlo, 1969; Vargas Santos, Abel, 1982-1989; Veatch, Jeanette, 1959; Vemer, Randall, 1975-1998; Veneklasen, Paul S., Research Foundation, 1964-1995 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Venturino – Viola: Venturino, John D., 1996; Verdun, Jacques, 1984-1985; Verlag Shirzel, Verlag Bochinsky, 1984-1986; Vermont University of, 1969-1972; Vibra Screw, Inc., 1981-1985; Vibraphone, 1978; Vibration Equipment, 1985; Victor Records, 1962; Vienna, 1971; Viola da Gamba Players and News, 1966-2004; Viola Pomposa; Viola Research Soc., 1976-1977 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Violin: Violin Books, 1967; Violin Maker, 1968-1970; Violin Makers’ Shops, 1969-1994; Violin Maker, Job Analysis; Violin Makers’ Journal, 1959-1977; Violin Making Information, 1978 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Violin Making Schools (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Violin: Violin Making Supplies; Violin Octet, 1967-2004; Violin Octet Developing Fund, 1996-1997 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Violin Octet Developing Fund Part I (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Violin Octet Developing Fund Part II (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Violin Octet: CDs, 1999; Makers, 1999; Music, 1973; Website, 1999; Violin Family Measurements; Violin Players, 1964-1977; Violin Playing Machines; Violin Repairs and Services; Violin Society of America, 1985-1995 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Violin Society of America Part I, 1984-1996 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Violin Society of America Part II, 1984-1996 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Violin – Wall: Violin Teachers’ Guild, 1964; Violoncello Society, 1992-1998; Vitaly Import Co., 1996; Von Gierke, Henning Edgar; Wade, John, 1978; Wahl, Eugene A., 1989; Wake, Harry S., 1974-1998; Wali, Kameshwar, 1994; Walker, George, 1981-1999; Walker, William L., 1973; Walking, Robert A., 1988; Wall, Edward, 1973-1996 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Wallach - Washington: Wallach, Joelle, 1986-1987; Waller, Christopher, 1983; Waller, Mary, 1974; Walter, Jos A., 1961-1969; Ward, John, 1966-1989; Ware, William R., 1975-1988; Warga, Mary E., 1971; Warren, Kenneth, 1978; Warren, Margaret H., 1981-1992; Washuburn, Robert, 1989; Washington Star, 1976 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Washington – Weertman: Washington, State University, 1983-1995; Wassermann, Harry H., 1959; Watanabe, Kyozo, 1977-1999; Wayne State University, Robert F. Lawson, 1968-1969; Waxman, Jon, 1990; Weaver, Hermann, 1959; Weddler, Robert P., 1962-1983; Weertman, Roelof, 1958-1975 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Weinberg - Weinrich: Weinberg, Joseph, 1977; Weinbich, Yoder, 1987; Weingaertner, A., 1963; Weingart, Beatrice and Jerome, 2003; Weinrich, Arnold (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Weinreich, Gabriel, 1979-1997 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Weinstein - Western: Weinstein, Stanley, Arts Management, 1996; Weisshaar, Hans, 1989; Wellons, J. D., 1970-1972; Wenberg, Thomas J., 1985-1988; Wenzinger, August; Wertman, David, 1974; West Caldwell Calibration Lab., 1997; Westchester State College, 1969; Western Michigan University, 1975; Western Ontario University, 1977-1979 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Westall – Widholm: Westall, Jack, 1953; Westlake, R. B., 1963; Westminster, 1988; Westphal, Barbara, 1978; W.G. B. H. TV Boston, 1976-2002; Wheeler, John, 1984-1988; White, Timothy D., 1976-1993; Widholm, Gregor, 1990 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Widmark - Wilkens: Widmark, Peter, 1966; Wilcox, Gordon, A., 1975-1986; Wilcox, Pat, 1984-1991; Wiley, John & Sons, 1963-1998; Wilkens, Henning, 1975; Wilkens, Mark W., 1981-1992 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Wilkins – Williams: Wilkins, Robert, A., 2004; William Paterson College of N. J., 1971; Williams, Carl and Betty, 1968-1988; Williams, Earl, 1968-1991 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Wilson, Ellery, 1972-1991 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Wilson, Horace, 1976-1992 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Wilson – Wire: Wilson, Geoffrey, L., 1976-1988; Wilson, James, 1991; Winckel, Fritz, 1951-1976; Wingard Co., Industrial Acoustics, 1965-1966; Winkler, Klaus, 1991; The Wirth; Wire for Strings (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Wisconsin - Women: Wisconsin, 1979-1981; Wittamer, Monsieru M. L., 1974; Wittenberg University, 1968; WNCN, 1972; WNYC, 1970-1981Wolf Note 1977; Wolf, Thomas, 1980; Wolfeboro Arts & Crafts, 1980-1981; Wolfeboro Community TV, 2003; Wolfeboro Lions Club, 1995; Women, 1991-1998 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - The Woman’s Club of Upper Montclair, 1956-2000; The Women’s Project of N. J., 1985-1998; Women in Science Association of, 1997 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Wood – Woodcraft: Wood, Christopher, 2003; Wood, A and M Wood Specialty, 1995; Wood Inquiries, 1980-1997; Wood for Violins, 1965-1998; Woodcraft Supply Corp., 1976 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Woodhouse, James Part I, 1985-1992 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Woodhouse, James Part II, 1981-1992 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Wollen – Wright: Wollen, Anthony, 1963-1975; Worman, Walter, 1970-1989; Wraight, Denzil, 1988-1998; Wright State University, 1977 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Wule – Yale: Wule, Stanley S., 1966-1993; Wyman Instruments, 2004; Wyoming University, 1968-1982; Wyszkowski, Paul S. W., 1986-1988; Yadzinsky, Edward, 1979; Yafet, Judith, 1992; Yale Lecture, 1991; Yale School of Music, 1964-1992 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Yale – Young: Yale University Music Library, 1988-1995; Yano, Hiroyuki, 1992; Yarovoi, Denis, 1987; Yeaple, Thomas, 1979; YM-YWHA, 1991-1992; Yoder, Jeremy, 1995-1996; Yost, Paul, 1976; Young, Cynthia, 1969; Young, David Russell, 1975-1979 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Young – Zaslavsky: Young, Robert W., 1958-1981; Yu, George, 1994; Zander, Ben, 1966; Zaret, Peter, 1988-1999; Zaslav, Bernard Naomi, 1963-1998; Zaslavsky, Sam, 1967-1998 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Zenith – Zoerning: Zenith Radio, 1976; Zieske, Arthur, 1980; Zimmermann, Martin H., 1978; Zimmermann, Margaret, 1975-1991; Zoerning, Robert J., 1972-1989 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Zuger, Robert, 1985-1998 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Zukofsky, Paul, 1974- 1989; Zurich Chamber Orchestra, 1964-1965 (Box 71, Folder 2)
- Series 3. Research and Writings: Notes, Published and Unpublished Papers
  - “On Improving Violins,” with Saunders, Frederick A., 1952, (reprint); “A Study on Tap Tones,” with Hopping, Alvin, S. and Saunders, Frederick A., 1958, (reprint) (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - “Subharmonics and Plate Tap Tones in Violin Acoustics,” 1960, (reprint); Resonance Frequencies, 1962, (notes, correspondence, and typescripts); “The Physics of the Violin,” 1962, (photocopies of books’ table of content, reprint, and typescript); “The New Violin Family,” 1965, (reprint) (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - The Story of a New Violin Family” (notes, correspondence, and typescripts), 1965 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - The Eight New Instruments of the violin Family. Memorial concert for Frederick A. Saunders, 1966, (program, article, and announcements); “Musician-Physicist,” 1966m (reprint); “Low-down on Bass,” 1966, (reprint); “The Squeal Heard ‘Round the World,” 1966, (reprint and program); “Founding a Family of Fiddles,” 1967, (typescript press release, photocopy of article); “A New Concert Violin,” 1967, (reprint) (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Chart Recorder Strips, 1969 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - The Bowed Strings: Yesterday, Today, Tomorrow, (annotated typescripts, notes, reprints, and correspondence), 1971 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - “Vibrations in Unassambled Violin Plates Compared by an acoustical Method and Hologram Interferometry, 1971, Acoustical Society of America (abstract and program); “Musical Acoustics, Part II. Violin Family functions,” 1973, (reprints); Vol. I Working Papers, 1975, (annotated typescripts, notes, and correspondence) (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - “The Acoustics of String Instruments,” 1975, (typescript); The Wolftone, 1976, (typescript); graphite Composites in Musical Instruments, 1976, (typescript); Long-Time-Average-Spectra, 1976, (typescript); Musical Acoustics, 1976, (outline for book, correspondence, typescripts); Another Piece of the Free Plate Tap Puzzle, 1977, (typescripts, correspondence) (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Scientific American Worksheets Part I, (reprints and typescripts by various authors), 1977 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Scientific American Worksheets Part II, (correspondence, reprints and typescripts), 1977 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - 9th International Congress on Acoustics, Madrid, July 1977, (typescripts); “The Physics of Music,” 1978, (reprint of book announcement); Acoustics and the Violin Maker, with M.E. McIntyre and J. Woodhouse, 1979, (typescript); “controlling Strings, Wood and Air,” 1979, (reprint); A Possible Rationale for Tuning Violin Free Plates to a Given Narrow Frequency Range, (typescript); “Plate Modes and Tuning” First Draft, 1979, (annotated typescripts and notes) (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - 350 Years of the Violin: A Modern Perspective, (notes and typescripts), 1980 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Plate Tap Tones, Interferograms and Eigenmodes in Violin Acoustics, 1980, (typescript); JASA Worksheets, (correspondence, notes, typescripts); Sound Generation in winds, Strings, and Computers, (announcements and typescripts) (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - The Acoustics of Violin Plates, (annotated typescripts, notes, and correspondence); Sound Generation, Corrected Copy, (annotated typescripts, and correspondence), 1980 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - SCI American, Work Sheets, (annotated typescripts and notes), 1981 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Scientific American Article, “The Acoustics of Violin Plates,” (annotated typescripts, notes, and correspondence), 1981 (Box 75, Folder 3)
  - The Violin Octet, 1981, (announcement and publication); a Note on Plate Theory and the Eigenmodes of Free Violin Plates, 1981, (typescript); “The Acoustics of Violin Plates, 1981, (correspondence and typescript); Tracking “Enclosed Air-Plate” coupling with Interior Gas Exchange, with G. Bissinger, 1983, (typescript);” A History of Violin Research,” 1983, (reprint, notes, and CAS membership list); “Evidence for the Coupling Between Plate and Enclosed Air Vibrations in Violins,” with G. Bissinger, 1983, (reprint); “Air Plate – Neck fingerboard Coupling and the ‘Feel’ of a Good Violin,” with G. Bissinger, 1985, (reprint); Octet – Backgrounds, 1986, (reprint, correspondence, notes, typescripts and publication); “Free Plate Tuning Frequencies for the Violin Octet Instruments,” 1986, (reprint); “A1 Cavity-Mode-Enhanced Fundamental in Bowed Violin and Viola Sound, with G. Bissinger, 1988, (reprint) (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - “A Study of the Cavity Resonances of a Violin and their Effects on its Tone and Playing Qualities,” 1990, (reprint); “Acoustical Effects of ‘Dressing Down’ a Fingerboard and/or Thinning the violin Neck,” 1990, (reprint of abstract); “Research Briefs for the Violin Maker,” 1990, (reprint); “Methods of Changing the Frequency Spacing (Delta) Between the A1 and B1 Modes of the violin,” with Oliver E. Rodgers, 1992, (reprint); “A 30-Year Experiment in the Acoustical and Musical Development of Violin-Family Instruments,” 1992, (reprint, images, notes, and correspondence); The New Violin Octet. Music in the Church at Aust, Saturday November 20th, 2004, (typescript and printed e-mails); “Eight is Enough,” by Paul Hormick, on Hutchins’ Consort, 2005, (reprint, correspondence, and typescript) (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Tenor Violin, (reprint, correspondence, drawings of the tenor violin), 1969-1976; In the following folders box 76 folder 2 - box 77 folder 3 Hutchins gathered research by subjects and it includes her writings as well as other authors (Box 76, Folder 2)
  - Psychoacoustics of Violins, (reprints, notes, and diagrams), 1969-1985 (Box 76, Folder 3)
  - Tuning Plates, Eigenmodes, (reprints, notes, and diagrams), 1969-1985 (Box 76, Folder 4)
  - Guitars, (reprints, notes, and diagrams), 1969-1984 (Box 76, Folder 5)
  - Other Instruments, (reprints), 1969-1983 (Box 76, Folder 6)
  - Air Resonance in Musical Instruments, (typescript) (Box 76, Folder 7)
  - Strings, (reprints), 1978-1982 (Box 76, Folder 8)
  - Varnish, (reprints), 1970-1984 (Box 76, Folder 9)
  - Octet, 1965-1978 (Box 77, Folder 1)
  - Viols; Equipment (Box 77, Folder 2)
  - Conferences Photos, 1974-1986 (Box 77, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous: Slide Presentation; Undated Typescripts; Diagrams; Fragments; Slides (Box 77, Folder 4)
- Series 4. Other Authors’ Research and Writings: Notes, Published and Unpublished Papers
  - Sir, Léo, “Le Violon et le Violoncelle peuvent-ils être modifiés?, 1924, (photocopies and typescript of translations); Dautrich, Fred L., Bridging the Gaps in the Violin Family, 1935, (photocopies); Sunders, F. A., “A Scientific Search for the Secret of Stradivarius,” 1940, (reprint); Sunders, F. A., “Studies of the Instruments of the Curtis String Quartet,” 1940; Sunders, F. A., “Improved techniques in the Study of Violins,” 1941, (reprint); Sunders, F. A., “The Mechanical Action of Instruments of the Violin Family,” (reprint); Sunders, F. A., “Analysis of the Tones of a Few Wind Instruments,” 1946, (reprint); Cadek, Ottokar, “The Deterioration of Violin Strings in Actual Use,” 1952, (reprint); Sunders, F. A., “Recent Work on Violins,” 1953, (reprints; Sunders, F. A.,”A Letter to the Editor Commenting on the Recent Article by R.B. Chatwin,”, 1956, (reprint); McKusick, Victor A. and Wiskind, Kenneth H., “Félix Savart (1791-1841),Physician-Physicist. Early Studies Pertinent to the Understanding of Murmurs,” 1959, (reprint); Sunders, F. A., “Remarks to Recent Correspondents, 1960, (reprint); Sunders, F. A., “Violins Old and New an Experiment Study,” 1962, (reprint); Schelleng, John C., “The Violin as a Circuit,” 1963, (reprint);Woollen, Anthony, “Should the Viola and the Cello be Scrapped?”, 1963, (reprint); Fryxell, Robert E., “Some Thoughts on the Requirements of A Good Varnish,” 1965, (reprint); Sunders, F. A., “Violins Old and New An Experimental Study,” 1966, (reprint); Schelleng, John C., On the Physical Effects of Violin Varnish, 1966, (typescript); Schelleng, John C., “The Bowed String,” 1967, (reprint) (Box 77, Folder 5)
  - Doschek, Anthony, “Some Physical Aspects of the Vibrato,” 1968, (reprint); Schelleng, John C., “Acoustical Effects of Violin Varnish,” 1968, (reprint); Schumacher, R. T., “Some Aspects of the Bow,” 1969, (reprint); Margrave, Wendell, “In Footsteps of Stradivarius,” 1971, (photocopy of clipping); Schelleng, John C., “The Bowed String and the Player,” 1973, (reprint); Schelleng, John C., “The Physics of the Bowed String,” 1974, (reprint and annotated typescript); Fryxell, Robert, “The Structure of Bow Hair,” 1974, (reprint); Woollen, Anthony, “New Instruments Unveiled in Britain,” 1974, (reprint); Weinreich, Gabriel and Arnold, Eric B., Method for Measuring Acoustic radiation Fields, 1979, (typescript); Savart, Felix, “The Violin,” 1982, (reprint); Rossing, Thomas, Bowed String Instruments, 1987, (typescript); Zalkind Spear, Deena, “Achieving an Air/Body Coupling in Violins, Violas and Cellos: A Practical Guide for the Violin Maker,” 1987, (reprint); Shaw, E. A. G., “Cavity Resonance in the Violin: Network Representation and the Effect of Damped and Undamped Rib Holes,” 1989, (reprint) (Box 77, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Undated: Taylor, Joseph. “The Principles of Violin Construction,” (photocopies); Savart, Felix, L’Institut, (typescript); Nelson Tuck, Jay, New Designs for Old Instruments, (reprint); Benade, Arthur, Wind Instruments and Music Acoustics, (bound typescript) (Box 78, Folder 1)
- Series 5. Photographic Materials
  - Misc. Photographs (Box 78, Folder 2)
  - Negatives #1-341, (4” x 4”); #1-15 (2”x2”) (Box 93)
- Series 6. Media
  - Reel to Reel Tapes: Julliard Symposium, Sundberg, 1977, (5” tape); Bill Hutchins Songs, 1971, (5” tape); Johannes Brahms, Violin Sonata, 1978, Nancy Clarke, violin, Dorothy Priesing, piano (5” tapes I and II); Hutchins-Zoernig Visit, 1973, (5” tape); Wilkens, Binaural Sounds, 1975, (5” tape); Hutchins Lecture, (5” tape); 3 unidentified tapes, (5 “ tape); Audio Cassettes: Four Sets of Strings: Boston ASA Meeting Tokyo String Quartet, Jun6 6, 1994; CAS International Symposium on Musical Acoustics, University of Hartford, July 1986, 5 audio cassettes: Robert T. Schumacher, Measurements of the Parameters of Bowing, 1986; Arthur H. Benade, Musical Acoustics Today; Judith C. Brown, Fourier Analysis of the Bowed String; Hidemo Kubota, Velocity Measurement for the Bowed String and Plural Helmoltz Waves; Helmut A. Müller, How Violin Makers Choose Wood and What the Procedure Means from a Physical Point of View. (Box 79)
  - Reel to Reel Tapes: Johannes Brahms, Sonata for piano and violin no. 2 in A major, op. 100. Unity Church, Nancy Clarke, violin, Dorothy Priesing, piano, 1978 (10 1/2 “ tape); Ernest Bloch (10 1/2 “ tape); Randall Vermer Concert, 1981; Touchstone. The New Violins, 1966, (10 1/2 “ tape) (Box 80)
  - Reel to Reel Tapes: 2 unidentified tapes, (10 ½” tape); Cambridge, (7” tape); Concert with Hutchins’ Alto Violin and the Small Bass. Ithaca High School Orchestra, (7” tape); 1 unidentified 7” tape (Box 81)
  - Film: California Academy of Science, (16 mm), 1962 (Box 81)
  - Digital Materials (refer to original folders) (Box 82)
- Series 7. Posters
  - Oversize Materials (refer to their original folders) (Box 84)
  - Graphs (Response Curves, etc.); The New Violin Family Part I (Flat-box 85)
  - The New Violin Family Part II; Chladni Patterns; Holograms; Free Plate Modes (Folder 86)
  - Andrea Guarnerius; Scaling Ratios for the Violin Family; Violin Plates (Folder 87)
  - 9th International Congress of Acoustics; CAS Technical Conference, 1967; CAS Finance Reports 1976-1983 (Folder 88)
  - Violin Complete SUS 180 Eigenmodes VS Response Curve (Oversize-folder 89)